<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://uncoolis.cool/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://uncoolis.cool/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-05-29T08:15:14-05:00</updated><id>https://uncoolis.cool/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Samuel’s Blog</title><subtitle>uncoolis.cool is such an uncool domain</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Trend of Evolution</title><link href="https://uncoolis.cool/markdown/2020/05/28/evolution.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Trend of Evolution" /><published>2020-05-28T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-05-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://uncoolis.cool/markdown/2020/05/28/evolution</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://uncoolis.cool/markdown/2020/05/28/evolution.html">&lt;p&gt;When you see how evolution works and what it  achieved going from molecule structures, which randomly reproduce by docking to atoms they are swimming in, to mammals and plants, which pose diverse assortments of cells which themselves guard the actually reproducing molecules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just can’t stop wondering what is this process directed at? I guess the classical scientific answer would be: most likely nothing. 
Of course one should be warned that whatever process we humans look at we try to see goals of agents, even when there are none an the case of evolution might not be any different. So asking the weaker correlation question might anyways be interesting:
what is a global trend in evolution?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far it seems evolution is moving to more ‘complex’ world. While this might be true on the level of an individual creature, but on a global level this seeming ‘complexity’ might rather stem from orderliness, animals are large machines that are built and behave pretty orderly. 
We might define actual complexity as Kolmogorov complexity. The Kolmogorov complexity of a string is the shortest program by which this string could be generated, in some given programming language. So a sequence of 100 A’s is for python for example less complex less complex than a truly random sequence of letters, since the truly random sequence has to be hard-codes while the sequence of A’s might be generated by a function&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;lambda: “A”*100,
which is much shorter than the actual sequence.
We might for this thought experiment assume planet earth to be the intepreter of DNA code. 
Under the assumption that DNA is the major factor defining a creature we could say a human body for example takes no more
than 1.4 GB to describe (which is the uncompressed storage space available in a DNA, but actually a lot of it is unused in reality).
Trivially a body could store much more information by for example storing entirely different truly random DNA in each cell, but it does not.
Even different creatures of the same race, like all the blades of grass on a meadow, share a lot of their code (DNA), so a lot of the building plans of the meadow are actually relatively repetitive in comparison to the molecules the body is made of being randomly combined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is why I consider it an interesting idea to claim evolution slowly decreases complexity (in the Kolmogorov sense) of planet earth.
It feels wrong to say that the crown of evolution would be a planet that is completely uniform, s.t. it can be described with a minimum of code like the string of A’s.
If one thinks over the workings of the principles of evolution over time though the natural diversity induced by evolution might be just an intermediate level of evolution, but in the long run a single
recreator (creature, molecule, computer program..) builds a monopoly on living, because it is the most competetive across the environments of planet earth.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">When you see how evolution works and what it achieved going from molecule structures, which randomly reproduce by docking to atoms they are swimming in, to mammals and plants, which pose diverse assortments of cells which themselves guard the actually reproducing molecules.</summary></entry></feed>